Register of the Edward Eyre Hunt Papers, 1902-1953
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1946
  - Treves, Peter G., 1944-1946
  - Tuck, W. Hallam, 1934
  - Tunnell, James M., 1944
  - Turner, Donald D., 1942-1944
  - Turner, Ralph C., 1942
  - Ulich, Mrs. Robert, 1943
  - Unger, Leonard, 1945
  - Upman, Frank, Jr., 1946
  - Vail, Lloyd J., 1942-1944
  - Vaile, Roland S., 1942
  - Valk, Ivan, 1934
  - Vandellos, Jose A., 1942
  - Van Tress, Jane E., 1944
  - Van Zeeland, Paul, 1942
  - Vaughn, David B., 1946
  - Vaughn, W. S., 1944
  - Venneman, Mrs. Harry, 1943
  - Victory, John F., 1944
  - Vieg, John A., 1943
  - Vitale, E., 1945
  - Vogel, Harry A., 1942
  - Wadleigh, Mrs. H. Julian, 1944
  - Wadsworth, Eliot, 1943
  - Wall, Louise Herrick, 1942
  - Wallace, Lawrence, 1942
  - Walsh, Robert, 1943
  - Walter, Francis E., 1945
  - Walton, Frank, 1944
  - Wardwell, Charles A. R., 1942
  - Warren, George, 1942-1946
  - Waterhouse, G. B. 1942
  - Waukesha Motor Co., 1946
  - Wedgwood, Mrs. Ralph, 1944
  - Weindenhammer, Robert M., 1943-1944
  - Wervin, Charles W., 1945
  - Weston, Harold, 1946
  - Weston, S. Burns, 1942
  - Wheeler, Dan H., 1942
  - Wheeler, Frank, 1944
  - Wheeler, Leslie, 1943-1946
  - Wheeler, William H., 1935
  - White, Harry, 1944
  - Whitehead, Howard B., 1944-1945
  - Whitely, William N., 1943
  - Whitfield, William A., 1944
  - Wickard, Claude R., 1942
  - Wilcox, Walter, 1943
  - Wilhelm, Donald, 1943
  - Wilhelm, Edmund, 1942
  - Will, Mervin W., 1944
  - Willcox, Westmore, 1943
  - Williams, Charles H., 1944-1945
  - Williams, Whiting, 1934
  - Willits, Joseph H., 1943
  - Wilson, A. E., 1944
  - Wilson, J. T., 1941
  - Winant, John S., 1945
  - Wing, Andrew S., 1943
  - Wing, Mrs. David, 1943-1944
  - Winslow, Carlile P., 1944
  - Winton, David J., 1944
  - Wohlstetter, Albert, 1945
  - Wolfe, Harry C., 1943
  - Woodruff, Walter A., 1943
  - Woolley, Frank K., 1943
  - Worker's Education Bureau of America, 1929
  - Wright, Charles Will, 1944-1945
  - Wright, Robert C., 1943
  - Xanthaky, George, 1944-1945
  - You (Organization), 1944
  - Young, Donald, 1943
  - Young, Mrs. Trell, 1943
  - Zanca, Natal L., 1944
  - Zimmerman, Carrie M., 1943
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1946
  - Alfriend, James V., Jr. (Box 9)
  - Allied Control Commission (Italy)
    - Memoranda
    - Miscellaneous
    - Printed material
    - Reports (Box 10)
  - American Chamber of Commerce for Trade with Italy
  - American Federation of Labor
  - American Food in the World War and Reconstruction Period, bibliography
  - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee
  - American Management Association
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
  - Atlantic Charter, 1942
  - "The Bank of England and the Rationalization of the Basic Industries" Report by K. A. H. Egerton
  - Baruch, Bernard
  - Baruch, Ismar
  - Belgian-American Associates (Box 11)
  - Belgian-American Educational Foundation
  - Belgium - Comite National de Secours et D'Alimentation (Committee on Relief and Food)
  - Biographical material
  - Brazil (Box 12)
  - Brookings Institution
  - Business Historical Society
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
  - Coal
  - Collected letters, memoranda
  - Combined Boards
    - General
    - Combined Production and Resources Board
    - Combined Raw Materials Board
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium
    - General
      - Bibliographies
      - Notes by E. E. Hunt
    - Educational Foundation, Inc.
      - General
      - Correspondence, 1934
      - Printed material
  - Commission for Service in Czechoslovakia (Box 13)
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace
  - Committee on International Economic Policy
  - Committee on Supplies for Liberated and Conquered Territories
  - Common Council for American Unity - Interpreter Releases, 1949
  - Commonwealth Fund
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1942
  - Cooke, Morris L.
  - Cosmos Club, Washington, D. C.
  - Depressions - 1929
  - Economic Club, Chicago
  - Economic Councils
  - Economic Research Institute
  - Engineers
  - European Relief Council
  - European War, 1914-1918
    - General
    - Belgium
  - Federal World War Agencies and Their Records, 1917-1921 (Handbook) (Box 14)
  - Federated American Engineering Society - Committee on Elimination of Waste in Industry - Reports, 1921
  - Feis, Herbert
  - Food Research Institute
  - "Foreign Office Organization," (Booklet)
  - France
    - Conseil National Economique (National Economic Counsel)
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
  - Frey, John P.
  - Germany (Box 15)
    - General
    - Economic conditions
    - Food
  - George, David Lloyd
  - Great Britain
    - Mines Department
    - Parliamentary Debates
  - Hansen, Alvin H.
  - Harding, President Warren
  - Harvard Club
  - Herriot, Edouard
  - Hoover, President Herbert
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1915
      - Notes by E. E. Hunt
      - Speech to the Pittsburgh Press Club, April 18, 1918
    - Political campaign, 1920
      - General
      - Biographical material
      - Correspondence
      - Newspaper clippings
      - Speeches
  - Hull, Cordell
  - Hunt, Virginia L. (Mrs. E. E.) (Box 16)
  - Industrial Conference, 1919
  - Institute of World Policy
  - Institute on World Organization
  - Inter-Allied Committee on Post-War Requirements
  - Inter-American Statistical Institute
  - Inter-American Training Center
  - International Labour Office
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter
  - League of Nations
    - Miscellany
      - General
      - Notes by E. E. Hunt
    - World Economic Conference, 1927
      - Correspondence
      - Memoranda, reports
      - Miscellaneous
      - Printed material
      - Report by E. E. Hunt
    - World Economic Depression Inquiry, 1931 (Box 17)
      - Articles (translated from French publications)
      - Correspondence
      - Memoranda, reports
      - Notes, reports by E. E. Hunt
      - Printed material
  - Lewisohn, Sam A.
  - Lumber
  - Mead, James M.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18)
    - General
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Printed material
  - National Association of Manufacturers
  - National Association of Retail Grocers
  - National Bureau of Economic Research
    - Correspondence, 1928-1931
    - Printed material
    - Reports
  - National Economic Committee (Box 19)
  - National Education Association
  - National Food Conference, 1943
  - National Industrial Conference Board
  - National planning
    - Correspondence, 1931
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Notes, drafts by E. E. Hunt
    - Printed material
    - Reports
  - National Planning Association
  - National Policy Committee (Box 20)
  - National Research Council
  - Petroleum products - Oil
  - Philosophy of standardization
    - Articles
    - Correspondence, Memoranda, 1928
  - Plywood industry
  - Poland
  - President's Research Committee on Social Trends
    - General
      - Miscellany
      - Newspaper clippings
      - Printed material
    - Business records
    - Correspondence, 1929-1934 (Box 21)
      - General, 1930-1934
      - Individual file, 1930-1934
        - Brunner, Edmund deS., 1931-1932
        - Hamilton, Alice, 1930-1932
        - Harrison, Shelby M., 1930-1931
        - Keppel, Frederick P., 1930-1932
        - Merriam, Charles E., 1930-1932
        - Mitchell, Wesley C., 1930-1931
        - Odum, Howard W., 1930-1932
        - Ogburn, William F., 1929-1930
        - Ogburn, William F., 1931-1933 (Box 22)
        - Strother, French, 1929-1932
        - Truesdell, Leon D.
        - Venneman, Harry, 1932-1933
        - Von Huhn, R., 1932
        - Whelpton, P. K., 1930-1931
        - White, Leonard, 1930-1931
        - Wilson, Edwin B., 1930
      - Criticism, 1931-1932 (Box 23)
      - Monograph contributors, 1931-1933
      - Publishers, 1930-1934
      - Researchers, 1931-1932
    - Memoranda
    - Minutes of meetings (Box 24)
    - Notes, drafts by E. E. Hunt
    - Printed material
    - Proceedings
      - December, 1931 - February, 1932
      - March, 1932 - June, 1932 (Box 25)
      - June, 1932 (Box 26)
    - Publicity
    - Report summaries
    - Reports
    - Reports (Box 27)
  - Prohibition
  - Red Cross - U.S.
    - Correspondence, 1917-1946
    - Memoranda
    - News releases
  - Revue des Deux Mondes (Review of Two Worlds) (Box 28)
  - Roosevelt, President Franklin
  - St. Lawrence River
  - Salter, Sir Arthur
  - Shaw, Arch W.
  - Slichter, Sumner
  - Social Science Research Council
  - Society for the Advancement of Management
  - Society for the Prevention of World War III
  - Standardization Survey Committee
  - Stassen, Harold E.
  - Swope, Gerard
  - Technical Alliance
  - Twentieth Century Fund
  - United Nations (Box 29)
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1943-1945
      - Notes by E. E. Hunt
      - Printed material
    - Conference on Food and Agriculture, 1943
    - Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization
    - Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA)
      - Journal
      - Manual
      - Memoranda
      - Newspaper clippings
      - Personnel
      - Printed material
      - Reports
  - United States (Box 30)
    - American Relief Administration
      - Austria
      - Bulletin, March, 1923
      - Executive Committee
      - European Children's Fund
        - Personnel
        - Reports
          - General
          - Germany
          - Poland
          - Russia
    - Armed forces (Box 31)
    - Bureau of the Budget
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Civilian Conservation Corps
    - Congressional Record
    - Department of Agriculture
      - General
        - Press releases
        - Printed material
      - Bureau of Agricultural Economics
      - Farm relief (Box 32)
      - Food supply
        - Europe
        - Great Britain
        - United States
          - General
          - Correspondence, 1942-1943
          - Memoranda
          - Notes, reports by E. E. Hunt
          - Printed material (Box 33)
          - Reports
      - Office for Agricultural War Relations
      - Office of Foreign Agricultural Relations
      - War Food Administration
    - Department of Commerce (Box 34)
      - General
      - National Committee on the Utilization of Metals
      - National Committee on Wood Utilization
      - National Conference of Banking and Industrial Committees (Box 35)
        - Correspondence, 1932
        - Minutes
        - Reports
          - Section I - Background
          - Section II - The Conference
          - Section III - Organization for the Conference
            - Supplement 1
            - Supplement 2
            - Supplement 3
      - President's Conference on Unemployment (Box 36)
        - Coal Committee
          - Business records
          - Correspondence, 1924-1926
          - Memoranda
          - Printed materials
        - Committee on Business Cycles and Unemployment (Box 37)
          - General
          - Business records
        - Committee on Recent Economic Changes (Box 38)
          - General
          - Business records
          - Correspondence, 1921-1942
            - General, 1923-1939
            - Carnegie Corporation, 1921-1930
            - Dennison Manufacturing Company, 1929
            - Duffield and Company, 1928
            - Gay, Edwin F., 1927-1939
            - Harcourt, Brace & Company, 1928
            - Harper & Brothers, 1928
            - McGraw-Hill Company, 1924-1942 (Box 39)
            - Mayer, Raymond C., 1929-1930
            - Mitchell, Wesley C., 1927-1931
            - National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc., 1928-1932
            - Shaw, Arch W., 1928-1942
            - Worker's Education Bureau Press, Inc., 1929-1930
          - Memoranda, reports
          - Notes by E. E. Hunt
          - Personnel
          - Printed material
        - Committee on Seasonal Operation in Construction (Box 40)
      - President's Emergency Committee for Employment
    - Department of Labor (Box 41)
      - General
      - Bureau of Labor Statistics
        - Correspondence, 1942
        - Historical Study Number 78
        - Reports
          - 1941
          - 1942 (Box 42)
          - 1943
      - Children's Bureau
      - Committee on Technological Employment
    - Department of State (Box 43)
      - Bulletin
      - Division of Cultural Relations
      - Foreign Economic Administration
        - General
          - General
          - Correspondence, 1943-1945
          - Memoranda
          - Personnel
          - Press releases
          - Reports
        - Czechoslovakia
        - Italy
          - Correspondence, 1944-1945
          - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 44)
          - Memoranda
            - General
            - Intelligence memoranda (Box 45)
              - May - August, 1944
              - January - March, 1945
              - April - December, 1945 (Box 46)
              - January - June, 1946
          - Newspaper clippings (Box 47)
          - Notes, drafts by E. E. Hunt
          - Personnel
          - Policy documents
          - Reports
          - Staff meeting agenda
        - Russia
      - Office of Foreign Relief and Rehabilitation (Box 48)
        - General
          - Correspondence, 1943
          - Memoranda
          - Printed material
        - Greece
          - Memoranda
          - Notes by E. E. Hunt
          - Reports
    - Department of the Interior
    - Department of the Treasury
    - Economic planning
    - Export-Import Bank
    - Federal Reserve System
      - Bulletin
      - Weekly Review of Periodicals, 1942-1945 (incomplete) (Box 49)
    - Food Administration
    - National Archives
    - National Defense Program
    - National Planning Board (Box 50)
    - National Resources Planning Board
    - National War Service Act, 1943
    - Office for Emergency Management
    - Office of Price Administration
    - Office of Production Management
    - Office of War Information
    - Office of War Mobilization and Reconversion
    - Political parties
    - Senate
    - War Department
    - War Manpower Commission
    - War Production Board (Box 51)
      - General
        - General
          - Memoranda
          - Newspaper clippings
          - Printed material
        - Commodity control
        - European electric power
        - Foreign requirements
        - Public utilities (Box 52)
          - General
          - Memoranda
          - Newspaper clippings
          - Printed material
          - Reports
      - Board of Economic Warfare (Box 53)
        - General
        - Greece
      - Division Requirements Committee
      - Standard Products Committee
      - War Industrial Facilities
  - Venezuela (Box 54)
  - Voorhis, Jerry
  - Wachtell, Sidney
  - Wagemann, Ernst
  - Wallace, Henry A.
  - War Agencies Employee's Protective Association
  - Whitney, Caspar
  - Williams, Nathan Boone
  - Wilson, President Woodrow
  - World War, 1939-1945 - Postwar planning
  - Writers' War Board
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1921-1945
  - "The American Committee," January 12, 1934., 1 typewritten copy. (Box 55)
  - "Are We Safe for Leisure?" Two articles co-authored with Richard J. Walsh, n.d., 1 carbon copy of each article.
  - Book review of Hollow Folk by Mandel Sherman, Thomas Y. Crowell Company, New York, 1933., 1 carbon copy.
  - Drafts, notes
  - Drafts, notes (Box 56)
  - Drafts, notes (Box 57)
  - Drafts, notes (Box 58)
  - "Economic Changes," speech to the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, New York, December 3, 1929., 6 copies (1 typewritten. 5 printed), speech, notes.
  - "Food," parts IV-IX, ca. 1934, draft.
  - "The Germans in Antwerp," n.d., 1 typewritten copy.
  - "The Influence of Scientific Management in American Industry," Chapter III, 1929., 4 carbon copies.
  - "A Letter to Laurence Stern," August, 1933., 1 carbon copy.
  - Miscellaneous - untitled speech notes, draft of article.
  - "The National Commission on Law Observance and Enforcement," typewritten notes for article.
  - "Notes on Economic and Social Surveys," New York, December 8, 1927., 2 printed copies.
  - "Our Changing America," speech to the New England Branch of the Worker's Education Bureau, Worcester, Mass., October, 1929., 3 copies (1 typewritten, 2 carbons).
  - "Presidnet Hoover and Unemployment," 1930., 1 carbon copy.
  - "Recent Economic Changes in the United States," article for the New York Times Current History Magazine, May 31, 1929., 3 carbon copies.
  - "Scientific Management and World Economics," article in the Bulletin of the Taylor Society, June, 1927., 1 printed copy.
  - "Sounding a New Keynote for Industry Today," n.d., 1 carbon copy.
  - Speech to the Employing Printer's Association, New York, February 27, 1922., 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the Industrial Engineers, New York, October 25, 1921., 1 typewritten copy.
  - Speech to the Industrial Engineers, Springfield, mass., October 7, 1921., 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon).
  - Speech to the Taylor Society Meeting, New York, December, 4, 1929., 1 carbon copy.
  - "Trade with Italy," speech to the American Chamber of Commerce for Trade with Italy, Inc., New York, May 22, 1945., 1 carbon copy.
  - "Under the Microscope," article for The Forum, May 10, 1929., 1 carbon copy.
  - Untitled manuscript of a book on U.S. history, approximately 1915-1932. (Box 59)
    - Parts I, II
    - Parts III, IV (Box 60)
    - Parts V - XVII (Box 61)
    - Book II, Parts I, II, III, V, VI (Box 62)
  - "The World Economic Conference at Geneva" article prepared for Nation's Business, June 27, 1927., 1 carbon copy.
- AUDIO-VISUAL.